<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-04T23:43:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Constitutes Ethical SEO?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/12/12/what-constitutes-ethical-seo/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-12T00:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/12/12/what-constitutes-ethical-seo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
    <em>&quot;nice post!!thanks for the info..that&#39;s great and cool&quot;<br />
    &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; -Random Spammer</em>
</blockquote>


<br />


<p>As
a web developer / someone who has a blog, I understand dealing with
spam is one of the necessary evils of having a comments enabled on my
site. For the most part, my site has remained far enough under the
radar that most spammers do not waste their time. More recently,
however, there has been a gradual influx of comment spam with a title
something along the lines of &quot;[Company Name] SEO Test.&quot; There is worse
spam for sure but it was definitely annoying. <br /></p>

<br />


<p>A quick Google
search pointed me to a Web Development and Search Engine Optimization
company hosting an SEO competition. I checked the rules and sure enough,
there was a rule stating that only Ethical SEO Techniques would be
permitted. Quickly, I emailed the organization one of the comments
(with url, ip, email, etc) exepecting the offending parties would be
removed from the competition, eliminating additional garbage comments.
I was shocked to receive their reply.<br /></p>

<blockquote>
    <em>Unfortunately
    this is not against the rules of the competition &ndash; I would encourage
    you to remove the spamming links for your website to discourage this
    behaviour but as I said I can&rsquo;t actually penalise this person
    for making posts on other peoples websites.</em><br />
    <br />
    <em>Sorry about the spam.</em><br />
</blockquote>


<p><strong>Gaming the System</strong><br />
In
my opinion, Search Engine Optimization should be about perfecting a
website and the website&#39;s content; not tricking google into thinking
more people find your content useful than actuality. <a href="http://www.youngentrepreneur.com/blog/2008/12/11/seo-advice-josh-can-help/" target="_blank">Optimizing tags
and titles</a> is one thing but gaming the system to garner search ranking is wrong
and is detrimental to the web as a whole. Just because commenting is
legal and allowable does not make it ethical. Unfortunately, this
practice will continue to exist as long as it gets results and
organizations act as enablers to those who would use these tactics for
financial gain (not to mention increased search engine ranking for the
enabling organizations). <br /></p>

<br />


<p><strong>Link Spam is Digital Graffiti</strong><br /></p>

<div style="float: right">
<img src="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/files/spra-paint.jpg" alt="" />
</div>


<p>Imagine
for a second if companies condoned this practice outside of the Web --
what if McDonalds or Nike paid for their logos to be spray painted on
other&#39;s property? To make matters worse what if after receiving
numerous complaints they held a press conference and said &quot;soap and
water removes the paint&quot; or &quot;just hire some guards and the problem will
go away.&quot;? I think it&#39;s safe to assume that practice would not be
received so kindly (h/t <a href="http://www.codehinting.com" target="_blank">Matt Braun</a> on the graffiti analogy)!
Fortunately a link is not as hard to remove as paint but the concept is
similar. <br /></p>

<br />


<p><strong>Solutions anyone?</strong><br />
Social networks such as
<a href="http://www.digg.com" target="_blank">Digg</a>, <a href="http://www.dotnetkicks.com" target="_blank">DotNetKicks </a>and <a href="http://www.dzone.com" target="_blank">DZone </a>have always been plagued by those who would
try to circumvent the rules for personal gain. Where honeypots and
captcha systems would traditionally help against
bots, an increasing number of spammers seem to be actual people. The
administrators of these social networks are constantly coming up with
more sophisticated ways to combat spam but what should small blogs and
websites do?<br /></p>

<br />


<p>Currently,
there are a number of methodologies for preventing blog spam that work
with varying degrees of effectiveness but none are ideal. Obviously,
you can moderate comments -- this works okay but is painful if you are
getting a lot of spam or a lot of comments. Also, make sure your
comment links have a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; attribute (h/t <a href="http://codeclimber.net.nz" target="_blank">Simone Chiaretta</a>). Google
does not take nofollow links into account when calculating page rank.
Although this does not reward the spammer, it does not prevent spam. <br /></p>

<br />


<p>What I would like to see is a centralized comment system like Disqus or
IntenseDebate that lets a user login with OpenID, Google Friend
Connect, Microsoft LiveID, Facebook Connect (whichever the user wants).
There would be a standard vote up / down vote for every comment a user
makes where the overall votes across all sites would determine the
users rating. Casting a down vote would remove a minimal amount of
points from the voter to prevent someone from going on a down vote
rampage (exactly how <a href="http://www.stackoverflow.com" target="_blank">StackOverflow </a>works). Site owners could set
restrictions that would prevent users with a rating less than a
specified number from posting on their site. This may be idealistic and
introduce a new realm of privacy concerns but if done properly, I think it
would help eliminate a great deal of spam.<br /></p>

<br />


<p><strong>Wrapping things up<br />
</strong>Although there are many less-than ethical tactics to increasing a
site&#39;s ranking, site structure and site content are the best methods of
SEO. I would love to hear your thoughts, ideas and any suggestions you
have in eliminating link spam.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IE8 vs Firefox 3.0b5 JavaScript Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/04/12/ie8-vs-firefox-3-0b5-javascript-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-12T23:24:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/04/12/ie8-vs-firefox-3-0b5-javascript-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
Last time I posted on the latest browser from Microsoft vs. Mozilla&#39;s latest I had compared page download times between the two browsers. This time, I would like to take a brief look at how they stack up in regard to JavaScript. 
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://ejohn.org/" target="_blank">John Resig</a> (of <a href="http://www.jquery.com" target="_blank">jQuery </a>/ <a href="http://www.mozilla.org">Mozilla </a>fame) announced the <a href="http://dromaeo.com/" target="_blank">Dromaeo: Javascript Performance Testing</a> suite yesterday. The suite runs some of the same tests as the <a href="http://webkit.org/" target="_blank">WebKit </a>team&#39;s <a href="http://webkit.org/perf/sunspider-0.9/sunspider.html" target="_blank">SunSpider</a>, however, there are some improved methodolgies (see the suite&#39;s <a href="http://wiki.mozilla.org/Dromaeo" target="_blank">wiki </a>for more info on this). I don&#39;t know how often I feel like doing DNA Sequence Alignment in JavaScript but I think it would be a good way to quickly get some metrics of how both FireFox and IE8 handle the code.
</p>


<h2>The Comparison:</h2>


<p>
I ran the tests in groups because there were certain ones that were not finishing under IE8. To be quite honest, I&#39;m not 100% sure if this is an Internet Explorer issue, or an issue with the tests. Both are a work in progress so I would rather not make assumptions at this point. Anyways, the results of the tests are listed below: 
</p>


<table border="1" style="border: 1px none ; border-spacing: 0px">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <th>Test Name <br />
            </th>
            <th>Firefox 3.0 beta 5</th>
            <th>Internet Explorer 8</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Fannkuch v122</td>
            <td>802.80ms</td>
            <td>1032.20ms</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Base 64 Encoding and Decoding v122:</td>
            <td>2942.00ms</td>
            <td>Would not finish</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>DNA Sequence Alignment v116:</td>
            <td>420.00ms</td>
            <td>Would not finish</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>N-Body Rotation and Gravity v122:</td>
            <td>270ms</td>
            <td>529.40ms</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Prime Number Computation (2) v122:</td>
            <td>305.80ms</td>
            <td>518.20ms</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Recursive Number Calculation v122:</td>
            <td>184.40ms</td>
            <td>417.80ms</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Traversing Binary Trees v122:</td>
            <td>156.80ms</td>
            <td>422.20ms</td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<h2>The Results</h2>


<p>
The initial results look like Firefox is performing the more advanced Javascript operations faster than Internet Explorer. That being said, Dromaeo, IE8 and Firefox 3.0b5 are still being developed so a lot could change before the release. For more metrics <a href="http://dromaeo.com/?id=250,246,251,256" target="_blank">view a comparison</a> on the Dromaeo site of Safari 3.1, Firefox 3.0b5, Opera 9.5 and IE8b1. Let me know what you think or if you&#39;ve encountered different results.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Browser Beta Battle - IE8 vs Firefox 3.0b5]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/04/02/browser-beta-battle-ie8-vs-firefox-3-0b5/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-02T22:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/04/02/browser-beta-battle-ie8-vs-firefox-3-0b5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
After reading <a href="http://www.stevesouders.com/" target="_blank">Steve Souders&#39;</a> article on <a href="http://www.stevesouders.com/blog/2008/03/10/ie8-speeds-things-up/" target="_blank">IE8 speed enhancements</a>, I became curious about how page download times in <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/products/winfamily/ie/ie8/default.mspx" target="_blank">IE8</a> stacked up against the latest beta of <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/all-beta.html" target="_blank">Firefox (3.0b5)</a>. I realize that both of these browsers are in beta so the release product may be signficantly different. Also, please keep in mind these results are not very scientific (obviously). To obtain download times, I used <a href="http://www.fiddlertool.com/fiddler/" target="_blank">Fiddler</a> for <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/products/winfamily/ie/ie8/default.mspx" target="_blank">Internet Explorer</a> and <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/1843" target="_blank">Firebug </a>for <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/en-US/firefox/all-beta.html" target="_blank">Firefox</a>.
</p>


<p>
First off, I loaded a several higher volume websites to compare page download times. Each page was loaded three times (for extreme statistical accuracy :P) and the average load time was calculated.
</p>


<h2 style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px">
Google News</h2>


<p><a href="http://news.google.com" target="_blank">http://news.google.com </a></p>

<br />


<br />


<div style="border: 1px solid #656565; background-color: #ededed; width: 355px">
0 Javascript Requests - 0 CSS Requests - 32 Images
</div>


<table border="0">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>Firefox:</strong></td>
            <td>1.08 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>IE8:</strong></td>
            <td>2.43 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<br />


<h2 style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px">
Amazon
</h2>


<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com" target="_blank">http://www.amazon.com</a><br /></p>

<br />


<div style="border: 1px solid #656565; background-color: #ededed; width: 355px">
12 Javascript Requests - 2 CSS Requests - 96 Images
</div>


<table border="0">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>Firefox:</strong></td>
            <td>5.59 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>IE8:</strong></td>
            <td>4.86 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<br />


<h2 style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px">
Mac.com 
</h2>


<p><a href="http://www.mac.com" target="_blank">http://www.mac.com</a><br /></p>

<br />


<div style="border: 1px solid #656565; background-color: #ededed; width: 355px">
15 Javascript Requests - 6 CSS Requests - 44 Images
</div>


<table border="0">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>Firefox:</strong></td>
            <td>5.74 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td align="right"><strong>IE8:</strong></td>
            <td>4.52 Seconds</td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<br />


<p>
Finally, I ran <a href="http://stevesouders.com/hpws/parallel-downloads.php" target="_blank">Steve Souders&#39; Parellel downloads test</a>; the results were almost identical.
</p>


<table border="0" style="border: 1px solid ">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td bgcolor="#ededed"><strong>Firefox</strong></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td><img src="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/files/firefox.gif" alt="" /></td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<table border="0" style="border: 1px solid ">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td bgcolor="#ededed"><strong>Internet Explorer</strong></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td><img src="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/files/ie8.gif" alt="" /></td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>


<br />


<br />


<p>
It was really odd to me that Google News loaded almost two times as fast on Firefox while all the other sites loaded close to the same speed or slightly faster on Internet Explorer. The only difference I notice off the bat is the number of JS/CSS files; maybe its something to do with that? It would be very interesting to see how the browsers compare when rendering pages. Have you found results similar to this or know of a good way to test render time? Let me know what you think.
</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diving into Ruby on Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/02/06/diving-into-ruby-on-rails/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-06T19:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/02/06/diving-into-ruby-on-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
This past weekend I started really digging into <a href="http://www.rubyonrails.org/" target="_blank">Ruby on Rails</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;For&nbsp;a
while now, I have&nbsp;known a little bit of ruby (by reading <a href="http://poignantguide.net/ruby/" target="_blank">Why&#39;s Poignant
Guide</a> and messing around a little with Rails), however,&nbsp;I wanted to
have a much stronger understanding in it -- even if it&#39;s only for the
concepts.&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
&nbsp;
<br />
<strong>Why Rails -- Why Now?</strong>
</p>


<p>
Rails has been publicly available since July 2004; some may ask why
I am just now becoming interested in the framework. There are actually
several main reasons... 
</p>


<ol>
    <li>It is a good educational
    resource in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model-view-controller" target="_blank">MVC Pattern</a>. This applies to many implementations such
    as <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/10/14/asp-net-mvc-framework.aspx" target="_blank">Microsoft MVC</a>, <a href="http://www.symfony-project.org/" target="_blank">Symfony </a>and <a href="http://www.cakephp.org/" target="_blank">Cake </a>on PHP and a whole slew of <a href="http://merbivore.com/" target="_blank">other</a>
    frameworks.</li>
    <li>Rails is becoming a more viable option with <a href="http://jruby.codehaus.org/" target="_blank">JRuby </a>and the forthcoming releases of <a href="http://www.ironruby.net/" target="_blank">IronRuby</a>.</li>
    <li>The concept of <a href="http://glu.ttono.us/articles/2005/10/27/the-joy-of-migrations" target="_blank">DB Migrations</a> is very nice -- especially when you
    have encountered the difficulty involved in placing your <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/001050.html" target="_blank">database under source control</a>.</li>
</ol>


<p>
&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
<strong>Setting up the environment</strong>
</p>


<ol>
    <li>
    <div>
    I needed to configure my computer to run the rails apps. <a href="http://www.netbeans.org/" target="_blank">NetBeans
    </a>seemed like a good idea to me because of the simple JRuby integration
    (other options <a href="http://www.aptana.com/" target="_blank">Aptana Studio</a>, <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/" target="_blank">Eclipse</a>, your favorite text editor w/ <a href="http://instantrails.rubyforge.org/wiki/wiki.pl" target="_blank">Instant rails</a>).&nbsp;
    </div>
    </li>
    <li>
    <div>
    I already had <a href="http://www.mysql.com/" target="_blank">MySql </a>installed on my computer so there was no need
    to set up a database server (<a href="http://www.sqlite.org/" target="_blank">Sqlite </a>was a tempting option as well). 
    </div>
    </li>
    <li>
    <div>
    Created a series of databases (as needed)&nbsp;for the various test&nbsp;rails apps to write to.
    </div>
    </li>
    <li>
    <div>
    Downloaded and installed <a href="http://webyog.com/en/" target="_blank">MySqlYog </a>Community edition. I knew I was
    going to be handling most of my database stuff with the Rails
    ActiveRecord implementation and db migrations BUT I still wanted to see
    what was going on inside the db.
    </div>
    </li>
</ol>


<p>
&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
<strong>Initial Impressions</strong>
</p>


<p>After the initial hour or so of
setting up my environment, I wrote some quick test applications
(following some tutorials, at first obviously). I really liked the
principle of Convention over Configuration.&nbsp; This was apparent in many
areas of the framework such as the <a href="http://wiki.rubyonrails.org/rails/pages/UnderstandingGenerators" target="_blank">generator</a> / <a href="http://rake.rubyforge.org/" target="_blank">rake </a>tools and the easy
application configuration in the <a href="http://railscasts.com/episodes/85" target="_blank">.yam</a>l files. I can see how this may
not be the best choice for certain applications but for a lot of web
applications, it seems like it will be a good fit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 Tips for Better Web Project Quoting]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/01/27/6-tips-for-better-web-project-quoting/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-27T10:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/01/27/6-tips-for-better-web-project-quoting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">An often overlooked area of Web Projects is quoting.&nbsp; Many developers
continually hone their programming and design abilities, however, few
value quoting ability as a necessary tool.&nbsp; Quotes that are inaccurate
can cost you; if you are too high, you are either ripping off your
client (apart from the ethical reasons it is also bad for you because
it may eliminate any future business and referrals) or you will not be
awarded the job.&nbsp; Here are some steps for better quoting.&nbsp; </font>
</p>


<h2>
<br />
</h2>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#1 KNOW YOUR CUSTOMERS</span></h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">You
will not sell anything that does not meet the customers needs -- no
matter how good the price is.&nbsp; Knowing your customer is the single most
important aspect of quoting.&nbsp; Sometimes clients will ask for something
that they don&#39;t really need.&nbsp; Instead of simply recognizing what they
are asking for, it is important to understand what they would like to
achieve.&nbsp; As developers or designers it is our job to educate the
client; to show them a more efficient way to accomplish their goal or
maybe even point out some things that were overlooked.</font><br />
<br />
</p>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#2 KNOW YOUR ABILITIE</span>S</h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">Know
exactly what you are capable of.&nbsp; Do not propose something that you can
not deliver.&nbsp; I realize that it is the nature of technology that it
will always be evolving and we will always be learning new things;
every project brings about new challenges.&nbsp; That being said, it is a
disservice to both you and your client if there is a lot you need to
learn before you can accomplish your proposed solution.</font><br />
<br />
</p>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#3 BE THOROUGH</span></h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">Your
proposal must be thorough.&nbsp; Obviously, being thorough does not mean
using technical jargon that would be above the clients head (remember
you want to educate, not confuse).&nbsp; Clearly present what you intend to
do and why it would benefit your prospective client.&nbsp; All the bases
must be covered all assumptions must be stated; do not leave any wiggle
room for assumptions because that can lead to a mess later (I know its
somewhat repetitive but I can&#39;t state it enough).&nbsp;&nbsp; </font><br />
<br />
</p>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#4 PRESENT YOUR PROPOSAL PROFESSIONALLY (alliteration not intended)</span></h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">Your
proposal will be seen as a reflection of your work.&nbsp; Make sure you
place the same kind of time and effort in to the flow and layout of the
proposal as you would any other design piece.&nbsp;</font> <br />
<br />
</p>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#5 ACCOUNT FOR ROAD BUMPS</span></h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">According
to Murphy&#39;s Law, anything that can possibly go wrong, will go wrong.&nbsp;
Account for this in your time estimates.&nbsp; Take note of the areas where
there could be problems.&nbsp; Take some extra time while quoting to
research more about what the possible outcomes could be and create a
plan of action.&nbsp; This plan will give you a better idea of what
time-frame you&#39;re looking at.</font><br />
<br />
</p>


<h2><span style="font-weight: bold">#6 PRACTICE, PRACTICE, PRACTICE</span></h2>


<p>
<font face="arial,helvetica,sans-serif" size="2">Sometimes,
good quoting simply comes down to experience.&nbsp; The more jobs you have
quoted, the more data you have to work with to determine where you were
off and what areas you should focus more on.&nbsp; This may be common sense
but make sure you keep track of how many hours you quoted for a project
and how many actual hours it came out to be.&nbsp; Additionally, break down
the project into different sections.&nbsp; A more module approach will help
you determine where things went wrong.</font><br />
<br />
<br />
Hopefully this will
be helpful to you no matter how experienced at quoting projects you
are.&nbsp; Please post your thoughts or any other quoting suggestions that
you may have.&nbsp; (originally written 3/17/2007)
</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
