<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/ubuntu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-14T11:11:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sublime Text on Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/04/13/sublime-text-on-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-13T18:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/04/13/sublime-text-on-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I have switched from Windows 8 to Ubuntu on my laptop. Since the primary function of my laptop is development I have spent some time tweaking the software installed to fit my workflow.</p>

<p>The main tool I am using for all my development is <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a>. I like Sublime Text for many reasons -- it's lightweight, great community, tons of plugins and most importantly, <strong>vim keybindings</strong>; needless to say, it's pretty awesome.</p>

<p>To start with, I installed the package like so: <code>apt-get install sublime-text</code>. From there, I pretty much followed
<a href="http://blog.alexmaccaw.com/sublime-text">Alex MacCaw's excellent post on Sublime Text</a>. Mentioned in the post, <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control">Package Manager</a> is pretty much a must. As someone who has grown pretty dependent on ReSharper when doing .NET development, I find myself typing Ctrl + Shift + T to switch files (rather than the default Ctrl + P -- which, to me, seems a little weird because doing that in different environments brings up print dialog)</p>

<p><code>
{ "keys": ["ctrl+shift+t"], "command": "show_overlay", "args": {"overlay": "goto", "show_files": true} }
</code></p>

<p>Finally, since I will be writing most of my blog posts with Sublime Text (yea, this post about Sublime Text was written in Sublime Text :P), I installed <a href="https://github.com/revolunet/sublimetext-markdown-preview">Markdown Preview</a> through package control. If you notice the statement on the GitHub page, Linux users need to install a different version of Python to get the plugin to work. I wasn't super comfortable changing Python just for installing the Markdown plugin. Thankfully, <a href="https://github.com/revolunet/sublimetext-markdown-preview/issues/27#issuecomment-11772098">one of the comments on the plugin's GitHub</a> page has a pretty decent walkthrough on how to use pythonbrew to give Sublime Text the version of Python that the plugin needs (without necessarily using it throughout the system).</p>

<p>Now, I only wish there was a way to open up a console directly in Sublime Text -- because alt tabbing to terminal is just so difficult.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
