<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-04T23:49:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How did I get started in software development?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/07/08/how-did-i-get-started-in-software-development/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-08T20:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2008/07/08/how-did-i-get-started-in-software-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="http://www.codethinked.com" target="_blank">
Justin Etheredge</a> recently tagged me to write up how I got started in software development (you are probably familiar with the meme started by <a href="http://www.michaeleatonconsulting.com/blog/archive/2008/06/04/how-did-you-get-started-in-software-development.aspx" target="_blank">Michael Eaton</a>). Without any further explanation, here goes:
</p>


<p>
<strong>How old were you when you first started programming?</strong>
</p>


<p>
I first started programming when I was 10 or 11 (I don&#39;t remember exactly). 
</p>


<p>
<strong>How did you get started in programming?</strong> 
</p>


<p>
My interest in programming initially began as a general interest in computer games. My dad showed me how to get around in DOS and pulled up some games in QBasic. It wasn&#39;t long after that I started messing with the code to see what would happen if I changed things. From there, I tried writing some stuff on my own spending a lot of time in the syntax help.&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
<strong>What was your first language?</strong>
</p>


<p>
BASIC
</p>


<p>
<strong>What was the first real program you wrote?</strong> 
</p>


<p>
Depending on the definition, the first real program I wrote was a game that worked in an AOL chat room. When I was 13, one of my friends showed me this thing called a scrambler. The scrambler would let you enter a word, send the scrambled word to the chat and keep score of who got the word right first, etc. I don&#39;t know why but I thought it would be an interesting thing to try and replicate. About a month later, I had finished writing one using the VB and the Windows API. It was not very useful but I learned a lot that way I guess.
</p>


<p>
<strong>What languages have you used since you started programming?</strong>
</p>


<p>
C#, VB.NET, Java, JavaScript, Ruby, Perl, PHP, BASIC, C, C++, F# (and others)
</p>


<p>
<strong>What was your first professional programming gig?</strong>
</p>


<p>
When I was in Highschool/College I did some freelance websites/applications mainly for construction and contracting companies. After college my first full-time programming job was working at Franklin University on the development team (websites / web applications).
</p>


<p>
<strong>If you knew then what you know now, would you have started programming?</strong>
</p>


<p>
Absolutely.
</p>


<p>
<strong>If there is one thing you learned along the way that you would tell new developers, what would it be?</strong>
</p>


<p>
Be continuously learning. 
</p>


<p>
<strong>What&#39;s the most fun you&#39;ve ever had programming?</strong>&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
I honestly couldn&#39;t tell you -- there are a lot of projects that have been really fun. I especially like when there&#39;s some new kind of challenge I haven&#39;t encountered before.
</p>


<p>
<strong>Who are you calling out?</strong>&nbsp;
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://www.codehinting.com" target="_blank">Matt Braun</a>
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://blog.sanzenbacher.com" target="_blank">Scott Sanzenbacher&nbsp;</a>
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://blog.wekeroad.com" target="_blank">Rob Conery</a> 
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://www.noop.nl/" target="_blank">Jurgen Appelo </a>
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://www.dannydouglass.com/" target="_blank">Danny Douglass</a>
</p>


<p>
<a href="http://www.ayende.com/Blog/" target="_blank">Oren Eini</a> 
</p>


<p>
&nbsp;
</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
