<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: links | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/links/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-05T21:47:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tig: Great git command line tool]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/05/07/tig-great-git-command-line-tool/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-07T20:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/05/07/tig-great-git-command-line-tool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using git on most of my hobby projects for quite some time. I prefer the command line when possible, however, it is nice to visualize certain operations. <a href="http://sourcetreeapp.com/">SourceTree</a> and Github's <a href="http://windows.github.com">Windows</a> and <a href="http://mac.github.com">Mac</a> apps are very nice but I'm mostly on Ubuntu when using git. <a href="https://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/gitk.html">Gitk</a> is a decent option but sometimes tools such as this and the aforementioned GUI tools can be a bit over-the-top for a command line junkie such as myself. Something between the command line and full blown windowed GUI applications would be great; this seems to be where <a href="http://jonas.nitro.dk/tig/">tig</a> comes in.</p>

<p><a href="http://jonas.nitro.dk/tig/">Tig</a> has been around for a little while now but it just came across my radar via <a href="http://blogs.atlassian.com/2013/05/git-tig/">an excellent post on Atlassian's blog by Antoine Büsch</a> (as a side note, it's kinda cool to see this post on Atlassian's blog considering they make SourceTree). Antoine listed some compelling reasons for using tig but I was sold when he related tig to vim versus other development tools :)</p>

<p>To install tig on Ubuntu just open up a command line and run the obvious <code>apt-get install tig</code>. From there, navigate to a directory under source control (with git) and type <code>tig</code> -- you should see the main log view. Pressing 'h' will bring up help to see a list of available commands. You can stage changes by pressing 'c'. For a more exhaustive list of commands, check out <a href="http://jonas.nitro.dk/tig/manual.html">the official tig manual</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
