<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nerd | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/nerd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-18T16:26:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/04/06/moving-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T14:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/04/06/moving-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, it seems that the only time I've spent with my blog has been moving it to other platforms. Hopefully, that will change with the move to Octopress. Since this is mainly a programming / technical blog, I thought it would be great to host the blog with <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github pages</a>.</p>

<p>The Octopress install was pretty simple.. I mostly just followed the steps on the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">Octopress Setup page</a>:</p>

<ol>
<li>Install Ruby / rbenv</li>
<li>Install git</li>
<li>Clone the Octopress repo</li>
<li>Export posts from Wordpress</li>
<li>Convert the Wordpress xml file to Jekyll with <a href="https://github.com/theaob/wpXml2Jekyll">wpXml2Jekyll</a></li>
<li>rake generate / rake deploy / git commit origin source (from the examples)</li>
</ol>


<p>The part that gave me the most trouble was hiding legacy posts from the main page area. I wanted to keep some of the posts around for posterity but I didn't want them to show up with any sort of prominence on the blog. To that end, I created a folder called 'Legacy' and a folder within this newly created folder called '_posts'. From there, I moved the markdown versions of the posts into this folder. So far so good...</p>

<p>When I fired up the preview for Octopress, the blog was still loading all the legacy posts in the content area. I asked a question on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/15852698/octopress-custom-folder-for-old-posts">Stack Overflow</a> (that was subsequently shut down for not being programmy enough -- whoops) and tried a couple other things until I stumbled upon <a href="http://arshad.github.io/blog/2012/05/10/recipe-hiding-posts-from-the-octopress-front-page/">this post</a> on Hiding Pages from Octopress. Making the suggested changes produced the results I was looking for. Mission Accomplished -- for now. I may try to change the 'Recent Posts' widget so it does not show legacy posts, however, that won't be an issue when there is more content.</p>

<p>So, as of this post, I've used all Octopress for all of one new article but I really like the workflow; storing the posts in github is definitely an added benefit. Hopefully, I will continue writing beyond this post but I guess we will see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
