<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hardware | Ryan Lanciaux]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/categories/hardware/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-06T12:43:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Lanciaux]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ikea Standing Desk]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/05/03/ikea-standing-desk/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-03T21:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/blog/2013/05/03/ikea-standing-desk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past several years, I have grown quite accustomed to using a standing desk at home (I have an adjustable Ergotron that I absolutely love). I decided it was about time to make the switch at work, however, I didn't want to spend a lot of money on a desk. Thankfully, I had come across a <a href="http://iamnotaprogrammer.com/Ikea-Standing-desk-for-22-dollars.html">blog post by Colin Nederkoorn</a> on a standing desk he and a coworker built for $22. I like the design, however, I wanted more room for monitors. One of the comments on the blog led me to <a href="http://www.jinyoungkim.com/blog/2012/07/standing-desk/">Jinyoung Kim's modification of the Ikea desk</a> which used a wider table than Colin's design. I ultimately based my desk plans off Jinyoung's design, since it allowed for multiple monitors, laptops and other gadgets.</p>

<p>The main components of the desk are as follows (they should cost about $45 total):</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40104294/">LACK</a> coffee table -- this is the main piece of the desk.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/10056987/#/20094347">EKBY JÄRPEN</a> shelf -- for keyboard / mouse</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/10136135/#/10136135">EKBY BJÄRNUM</a> brackets</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://ryanlanciaux.github.com/files/desk-setup.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>As noted on Jinyoung's site, the shelf needs to be sawed down a bit to fit the dimensions of the coffee table. I like the brackets I used since it hides the rougher side of the shelf that was cut down. I would also echo his sentiment about using bolts to hold up the shelf as  they are sturdier than screws. Finally, as someone who has used standing desks for a couple years now I would HIGHLY recommend having a gel kitchen mat to stand on; especially if you're over hardwood or concrete flooring.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
